Prakash Agrahari

Portfolio- https://prakash-agrahari.vercel.app/

8559075258 | sshivamprakashh301@gmail.com | Atari Amiliya, Meja, Prayagraj, UP

Summary

Experienced (2+ Years) Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JSON, Github, and Bootstrap. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Electrical, Electronics, and Communications Engineering from Lovely Professional University.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer | 12/2022 - Present | VisionIndia Software Exports Ltd | Pune.

- Created wireframes of requirements given by client.
- Created dashboard and mutliple forms screen from scratch

Torinit Consulting Inc | 06/2022 - 09/2022 | Frontend Developer | Pune, Maharastra

Worked in the complex portal web app called Senara Triangle, having a portal for Admin, Super-Admin, and users.

- Worked on projects having state-management tools like redux
- Developed 30+ user-facing features via React JS.
- Developed the structures & layouts as per user requirements with 100% clients satisfaction

Ask-Fast | 12/2021 - 05/2022 | Frontend Developer | Bangalore, Uttar Pradesh

Worked in the complex portal web app called SOL, having a portal for Admin, therapist, psychotherapist.

- Developed protected route components for Authentication.
- Worked with international clients, and developed and troubleshot the problems clients had.
- Implemented Lazy loading into the application that reduced the initial loading time and made it 40% faster.

Frontend Developer | 09/2021 - 12/2021 | Riser Techub | Pune, Maharastra

Worked with various gaming web applications with complex UI as well logic contained.

- Configured Redux data flow between React components for logical separation of client-side logic and API calls.
- Worked and developed games like Roulette using React Js.
- made utilities of the reused functions and imported were needed to make the code cleaner.

Software Engineer | 01/2021 - 08/2021 | Rayabhari Technologies Pvt. Ltd | Bangalore

- Integrated new features like Payment, Zoom Call, Whatsapp, and Call in a mobile app!
- Troubleshoot and debug the Applications code for smooth exceptions and improved stability.
 Bug fix in Appointment Booking Functionalities

Skills

Javascript, ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, Ant-d, React Bootstrap, Redux, RTQ Query

Education

B.Tech | Lovely Professional University | 06/2018 | Jalandhar, Punjab